Casey Reyes

Santa Clara, CA ♦ caseyereyes@gmail.com ♦ Portfolio ♦ LinkedIn

Highly motivated software developer with five years of experience in the software industry and a passion for software engineering. Skilled in web applications, software development, and scripting. Possesses excellent interpersonal skills, a solutions-oriented mindset, and the ability to work on multiple tasks or projects either independently or as part of a team.

EXPERIENCE

Bitwise Industries Software Developer

Oakland, CA

March 2022 - June 2023

- Contributed as a software developer in a web development team, working closely on client projects to create engaging and functional web applications.
- Employed Agile methodologies to assist a specific client in designing and deploying their website, ensuring iterative feedback, frequent communication, and adapting to changing requirements to meet their unique needs.
- Effectively resolved client issues and roadblocks within their online platforms, leading to a significant 25% improvement in customer satisfaction levels.

Cadence Design Systems

Product Engineer

San Jose, CA

Jan. 2020 - Nov. 2020

- Collaborated as a product engineer within a team responsible for product development, contributing to the development of innovative solutions.
- Worked closely with clients to understand their needs and successfully implemented tailored solutions within the circuit design software.
- Developed and implemented custom scripts for clients, automating manual workflows and resulting in a 300% improvement in efficiency.

National Instruments

Senior Software Technician (Full-Time beginning 2018)

Santa Clara, CA

2016 - 2020

- Assisted clients by automating tasks and providing support within the circuit design software.
- Led the redesign and development of a custom software development service for a tier-1 customer.
- Successfully delivered the custom development service, optimizing workflows and enhancing overall performance.

PROJECTS

Capstone Project: Spotify clone music player | GitHub Repo

- Implemented React, TypeScript, Redux, Three.js, and Node.js to create and expand upon Spotify's capabilities.
- Seamlessly integrated music streaming and visualization components, offering an engaging and immersive user experience.
- Displayed my passion for both software development and music by merging the two interests into a fully functional application.

EDUCATION

San Jose State University

Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering, Minor in Mathematics

San Jose, CA

May 2018

TECHNICAL SKILLS & INTERESTS

Languages: Visual Basic, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, TypeScript, Python, C++, Java, PHP, Swift, Objective-C

Technologies/Frameworks: React, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Jest, Firebase, WordPress, Figma, Tailwind, SASS

Developer Tools: Git, GitHub, VS Code, Visual Studio, Google Cloud Platform, WPEngine

Libraries: Redux Toolkit, Axios, Styled-Components, Three.js

Interests: Dogs; yoga; travelling; beer; video games; anime; horror shows; music; DJing; Stormlight Archive